Guide to the Humphreys-Marvin-Olmstead Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- DAVID HUMPHREYS PAPERS, (1783-1818)-[ca. 1835]; Series I; 1.5' (4 boxes, 1 folio)
  - Diplomatic Correspondence
    - Enclosures
      - King, Rufus, 1755-1827
        - Electrostatic copy of extract of letter to [William Loughton Smith]. Original MS extract enclosed in William L. Smith to D. Humphreys, 1800 Apr 27, Box 2, folder 64 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      - Monroe, James, 1758-1831
        - Electrostatic copy of extract of letter to Timothy Pickering. Original MS extract enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1796 Jan 23, Box 1, folder 3, 1795 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 85)
      - Montgomery, Robert, U.S. Consul at Alicante
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Timothy Pickering. Original MS copy[?] enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1798 Apr 14, Box 1, folder 9, 1798 February 13 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      - Morris, Gouverneur 1752-1816
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Thomas Jefferson. Original MS copy enclosed in Edmund Randolph to D. Humphreys, 1794 Jul 19, Box 1, folder 1, 1794 March 7 (Box 3, Folder 87)
      - Morris, Robert, 1734-1806
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Timothy Pickering, enclosing an extract of a letter from James Rees to Robert Morris, dated 1797 Aug 28. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1797 Sep 23, Box 1, folder 6, 1797 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 88)
      - O'Brien [O'Bryen], Richard
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Stephen Cathalan, [Jr.]. Original MS copy enclosed in Thomas Pinckney to [David Humphreys?], 1792 Dec 24, Box 2, folder 53, 1791 September 27 (Box 3, Folder 89)
      - P[ickering], T[imothy], 1745-1829
        - Electrostatic copies of 2 letters to Joel Barlow. For the original letterpress copies, originally enclosed in a letter now missing from Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys dated pre-1796 Dec 9, see Box 1, folder 4, 1796 December 3, December 5 (Box 3, Folder 90)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Carlos Martinez de Yrujo [y Tacon, Marques de Casa Yrujo]. Original letterpress copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1797 Oct 31, Box 1, folder 6, 1797 July 18 (Box 3, Folder 91)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Elbridge Gerry, 1744-1814. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1798 Jul 16, Box 1, folder 10, 1798 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 92)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Rufus King, 1755-1827. Original MS copy enclosed in Rufus King to D. Humphreys, 1798 Feb 19, Box 2, folder 46, 1798 January 1 (Box 3, Folder 93)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Charles Cotesworth Pinckney (1746-1825), John Marshall (1755-1835), and Elbridge Gerry (1744-1814). Original MS copy enclosed in Charles C. Pinckney to D. Humphreys, 1798 Jun 1, Box 1, folder 52, 1798 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 94)
        - Electrostatic copy of extract of letter to Thomas Pinckney, 1750-1828. Original MS extract enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1797 Feb 17, Box 1, folder 5, 1795 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 95)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to John Robertson. For the original letterpress copy, originally enclosed in a letter now missing from Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys dated pre-1796 Dec 9, see Box 1, folder 4, 1796 December 5 (Box 3, Folder 96)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Charles Rutledge. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1797 May 5, Box 1, folder 5, 1796 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 97)
        - Electrostatic copy of extract of letter to [William Loughton Smith?]. Original MS extract enclosed in William L. Smith to D. Humphreys, 1798 Jul 22, Box 2, folder 59, 1798 June 2 (Box 3, Folder 98)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to William [Loughton] Smith. Original MS copy enclosed in William L. Smith to D. Humphreys, 1799 Jan 22, Box 2, folder 61, 1798 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 99)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Moses Young. Original letter-press copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1798 Apr 13, Box 1, folder 9, 1798 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - Pinckney, [Charles Cotesworth], 1746-1825
        - Electrostatic copy of extract of letter to William Loughton Smith. Original MS extract enclosed in William Loughton Smith to D. Humphreys, 1798 Jul 22, Box 2, folder 59, [1798] June 1 (Box 3, Folder 101)
        - Rees, James
          See: box 3, folder 88
      - Smith, William ILoughton], 1758-1812
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Captain_______; Kennedy. Original MS copy enclosed in William L. Smith to D. Humphreys, 1799 Jan 5, Box 2, folder 61, 1799 January 3 (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - Valliere,_______;, French Consul-General at Algiers
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to D. Humphreys. Original MS copy enclosed in Edmund Randolph to D. Humphreys, 1795 Apr 20, Box 1, folder 2. For recipient's copy of this letter, see Box 2, folder 66, 1794 December 22 (Box 3, Folder 103)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to "Resident of U.S. Congress [at Algiers?]". Original MS copy enclosed in Edmund Randolph to D. Humphreys, 1795 Apr 20, Box 1, folder 2, 1794 December 28 (Box 3, Folder 104)
      - Washington, George, 1732-1799
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to [Charles IV, King of Spain, 1788-1808]. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1797 Feb 17, Box 1, folder 5, 1797 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 105)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Hassan Pasha, Dey of Algiers. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1796 Jun 18, Box 1, folder 3, 1796 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 106)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Hassan Pasha, Dey of Algiers. For original MS copy, originally enclosed in letter now missing from Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys dated pre-1796 Dec 9, see Box 1, folder 4, 1796 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 107)
        - Electrostatic copies of 2 letters to [Maria I, Queen of Portugal, 1777-1816]. Original MS copies enclosed, respectively, in Edmund Randolph to D. Humphreys, 1794 May 10, Box 1, folder 1; Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1797 Feb 17, Box 1, folder 5, 1794 March 11, 1797 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 108)
        - Electrostatic copies of 2 versions of letter to [Yusef Karamanli, Pasha of Tripoli]. Original MS transcripts enclosed in Joel Barlow to D. Humphreys, 1796 Feb 16, Box 2, folder 38, 1795 March 30 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Letterbooks
      - Humphreys, David
        - "Report of Proceedings of D. Humphreys, Relative to the secret and public state-transactions and Negotiations In which he was concerned from the 26th day of July 1790, Vol. I," 284 pp., [1790 July - 1794 July] (Box 4, Folder 110)
      - [Randolph, Edmund, 1753-1813]
        - Copybook of "Letters from the Secretary of State, To Colo. David Humphreys," 12 pp., [1794 September 3-December 31] (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - [Washington, George, 1732-1799]
        - Copybook of letters to David Humphreys...
          See: box 4, folder 160
  - Diplomatic Miscellany
    - "List of the Members of the House of Representatives [and Senate] of the United States, for the year 1789" (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - O'Brien [O'Bryen], Richard, and other captives in Algiers
      - Copy of petition to U.S. Senate, with a list of "American Vessels captured by the Corsaires of Algiers in consequence of the Peace with Spain in 1785, and the Truce with Portugal in 1793.", 1793 December 29 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Simcoe, John Graves, 1752-1806
      - Extract of letter to Henry Dundas, 1st Viscount Melville, 1742-1811, copied from The London Gazette of 1794 Oct 18, 1794 August 30 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Newspaper clipping of letter from Edmund Randolph to George Hammond dated 1794 Sep 1; Hammond's reply of 1794 Sep 3, [1794 September 1, 3] (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829
      - Extract of letter to Thomas Pinckney, 1750-1828, 1795 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - O'Brien [O'Bryen], Richard
      - ADS entitled "Narrative of the proceedings of Joseph Donaldson Esqr. the agent of the United States relative to the obtaining of peace with the Dey and regency of Algiers". 19 pp., [1796 September-Nov?] (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Reinhard, [Charles-Frederic, Count, 1761-1837]
      - Copy of "Instructions addressees 1e 30 Thermidor an 7 a 1'Ambassadeur de la Republic a Madrid, pour etre communiquees a nos Agens Consulaires en Espagne. Dispositions politiques de 1a France a 1'egard des Etas Unis d'Amerique", [1799 August 17] (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Newspaper clippings of letters from Thomas T[erry] Davis (d. 1807) to James H. Stewart, President John Adams, and Carlos Martinez de Yrujo y Tacon, Marques de Casa Yrujo, dated 1800 Mar 31; with replies by Timothy Pickering and the Chevalier d'Yrujo, dated, respectively, 1800 Mar 13, [Apr 2], [1800 March 31, April 2] (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Newspaper clipping on the subject of the resignation of Timothy Pickering as Secretary of State, [1800] May 23 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Fragmentary notes on European religion, dated "Brest the 15th Prairal An 9", [1801 June 4] (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Copy of memorandum entitled: "Cases of Violation of the Spanish territory by the French, transmitted with the General Representation dated the 24th January 1801"; "Vessels of the United States finally condemned by the Council of War"; "Claims for damages now depending [before the Council of War].", [1802 January 1] (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - [Smith, John, 1735-1816?]
      - Statement re letter of [John?] Armstrong, 1758-1843, about the purchase of Florida by the United States, with a covering memorandum of the same date, 1808 April 25 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - "Extract from Carnot's Answer." Holograph of [John Pickering, 1777-1846?] secretary to William Loughton Smith, undated (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - "L'article 9 du reglement [du 26 Juillet 1778] est ainsi exprime…." Holograph of [John Pickering, 1777-1846?] secretary to William Loughton Smith, undated (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - General Correspondence
    - Banks, Sir Joseph, 1743-1820
      - File copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1817 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1792 September 28 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Bulkeley (John) & Son, of Lisbon
      - 5 ALS to D. Humphreys, 1797 August 2, August 23, August 28, 1798 January 30, February 3 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - File copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1797 November 10 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Burney, Charles, 1726-1814
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1807 August 15 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Bushnell, David, c. 1742-1824
      - 3 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1784 July 1, November 6, 1785 February 10 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Correa [de Serra, Jose-Francisco, 1750-1823?]
      - AL to D. Humphreys, [1791] May 11 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Derby, Mrs. M.C.[?]
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1814 April 1-2 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Dwight, Timothy, 1752-1817
      - AL to D. Humphreys, [pre-1775 Oct?] (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Eustaphieve, A[lexis?]
      See: box 4, folder 125
    - Eustis, W[illiam, 1753-1825?]
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1810 February 11 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Evstafiev, A[lexsiei Grigor'evich, 1783-1857?)
      - 2 ALS to D. Humphreys, 1814 April 1, April 18 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - [Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790?]
      - File copy of letter to [D. Humphreys], [c. 1788?] (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Greene, Catharine
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1791 December 19 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Hopkins, Lemuel, 1750-1801
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, [post-1802 Jun?] (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Humboldt, [Alexander, Freiherr von, 1769-1859]
      - 2 ALS to D. Humphreys, [1799 May 11], [1800 May 30] (Box 4, Folder 129)
      - File copy of letter from D. Humphreys, enclosing copy of a passport certificate of the same date, 1799 May 13 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Humphreys, Daniel, 1740-1827
      - 2 ALS to D. Humphreys, 1786 April 1, 1810 December 26 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Humphreys, John, 1744-1832
      - 3 letters from D. Humphreys (transcripts), 1786 August 4, 1790 November 29, 1791 August 18 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
      - File copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1801 May 8 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - La Rochefoucauld, Duc de
      See: box 4, folder 133
    - [La Roche-Guyon, Louis Alexandre?] La Rochefoucauld d'Anville, Duc de, 1743-1792?]
      - AL to D. Humphreys, 1786 February (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Lee, Ezra, 1748/9-1821
      - Memorandum [ADS?] to D. Humphreys entitled: "A Description of [David] Bushnell's Turtle", [1815 Feb?] (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Madison, James, 1750/1-1836
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1813 March 23 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Mazzei, Philip, 1730-1816
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, with postscript by W[illiam?] S[tephens?] Smith, 1755-1816, dated "Septr. 1st 1786", 1786 August 14 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829
      - Transcript of letter from D. Humphreys, 1783 February 10 (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - File copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1801 March 2 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Rutledge, J[ohn, 1766-1819?]
      - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1808 January 7 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Smith, William Loughton, 1758-1812
      - 2 ALS to D. Humphreys, [1802 February 4], 1808 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Trumbull, John, 1756-1843
      - Transcript of letter from D. Humphreys, 1804 July 14 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Washington, George, 1732-1799
      - 4 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1784 July 15, September 30, 1787 August 13, 1792 July 4 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Washington, Martha
      - File copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1800 February 22 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Unidentified
      - 2 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1787 September 28, 1788 September 29 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Third-Party correspondence
    - Baldwin, Abraham, 1754-1807
      - ALS to Joel Barlow, 1754-1812, 1794 June 9 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Bushnell, David, c. 1742-1824
      - Copy of letter to Thomas Jefferson, 1743-1826, enclosing: (1) "General principles & construction of a Sub-marine Vessel" and "Description of a Magazine, & its appendages, designed to be conveyed by the Submarine Vessel to the bottom of a Ship;" (2) "Experiments made to prove the nature and use of a Submarine Vessel.", 1787 October 13 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Casa Yrujo, Carlos Martinez de Yrujo y Tacon, Marques de
      See: box 4, folder 114
    - Davis, Thomas Terry, d. 1807
    - Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
      See: box 4, folder 145
    - Johnston, Nathaniel
      - ALS to John Humphreys, 1744-1832, with a "memorandum" by David Humphreys, dated 1810 Jun 27, 1810 June 25-27 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Madison, James, 1750/1-1836
      - AL to Joel Barlow, 1754-1812, enclosing copy of a letter from Albert Gallatin, 1761-1849, to William Pinckney, dated 1805 Nov 9, 1806 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Pickering, Timothy
      See: box 4, folders 113-114
    - Randolph, Edmund
      See: box 4, folder 113
    - Reinhard, Charles-Frederic, Count, 1761-1837
    - Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864
      - ALS to Colonel [George?] Gibbs, 1776-1833, 1818 February 24 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Simcoe, John Graves, 1752-1806
      See: box 4, folder 112
    - Smith, John, 1735-1816
      See: box 4, folder 116
    - Thornton, William, 1759-1828
      - ALS to C Redheffer, 1812 December 29 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Washington, George, 1732-1799
      - Transcript of letter to James Lloyd, [1745-1820?](Transcription by Lemuel G. Olmsted, 1856)., 1798 June 13 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Webster, N[oah], 1758-1843
      - ALS to Joel Barlow, 1754-1812, 1805 March 20 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Literary Miscellany
    - [Humphreys, David]
      - Heads for a poetic "essay" on the American Constitution, [post-1783] (Box 4, Folder 150)
      - Notes for "The Life of General Washington", [1786 Oct?] (Box 4, Folder 151)
      - Notes for a Life of Tench Tilghman (1744-1786), entitled "An account of the Life and character of the late Tench Tilghman Esq., Colonel in the Service of the United States and Aid de Camp to His Excellency General Washington", [post-1787 July 4?] (Box 4, Folder 152)
      - Draft of "A Poem on The love of Country", [1799?] (Box 4, Folder 153)
      - Advertisement for a poem, [c. 1800?] (Box 4, Folder 154)
      - A Valedictory Discourse, Delivered Before the Cincinnati of Connecticut, in Hartford, July 4th, 1804, at the Dissolution of the Society … (Boston, 1804). [pp. 1-4, 35-7, and "Appendix" (pp. [38-]60), are missing and replaced by electrostatic copies) (Box 4, Folder 155)
      - Drafts of Speeches[?], undated (Box 4, Folder 156)
      - Notes on European art and literature, undated (Box 4, Folder 157)
      - Unidentified poetic fragments, undated (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - [Washington, George, 1732-1799]
      - "Copies of original Letters & Orders to American Officers and others, respecting Captn. Asgill.", [1782 May 3-1786 July 20] (Box 4, Folder 159)
      - Copybook of letters to David Humphreys; with other matter. [Printed as the Appendix to The Miscellaneous Works of David Humphreys, Late Minister Plenipotentiary from the United States of America to the Court of Madrid (New York, 1804).], 1791 March 16-1800 February 11, undated (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Commissions, Diplomas, Certificates
    - U.S. Congress
      - Appointment of David Humphreys as Lieutenant-Colonel in the Army of the United States. Signed by B. Lincoln, Secretary at War, 1782 November 13 (Box 4a)
      - Appointment of David Humphreys as Lieutenant-Colonel Commandant of the Third Regiment in the Army of the United States. Signed by H. Knox, Secretary at War, 1787 April 2 (Box 4a)
    - U.S. Dept. of State
      - Commission of Joel Barlow and Joseph Donaldson as joint agents to negotiate and conclude a Treaty of Amity and Commerce between the United States of America and the Bey of Tunis. Signed by David Humphreys, 1796 February 10 (Box 4a)
    - Brown University
      - Diploma for the degree of Doctor of Laws conferred on David Humphreys. Signed by David Howell, Secretary, 1802 September 1 (Box 4a)
    - Massachusetts Society for Promoting Agriculture.
      - Honorary Certificate of Membership granted to David Humphreys. Signed by John Avery, Secretary, and Caleb Strong, President, 1803 August 27 (Box 4a)
    - Dartmouth College
      - Diploma for the degree of Doctor of Laws conferred on David Humphreys. Signed by John Wheelock, President, 1804 August 22 (Box 4a)
    - Connecticut (State)
      - Passport Certificate issued to David Humphreys. Signed by Jonathan Trumbull, Jr., 1806 June 23 (Box 4a)
    - Bath and West of England. Society for the Encouragement of Agriculture, Arts, Manufactures and Commerce.
      - Diploma of Membership granted to David Humphreys. Signed by Benjamin Hobhouse, President, 1806 December 2 (Box 4a)
    - Connecticut (State).
      - Appointment of David Humphreys as Brigadier-General of the Brigade of Volunteers. Signed by Thomas Day, Secretary, and John Cotton Smith, 1813 June 1 (Box 4a)
  - Genealogy, Biography, and Engravings
    - Humphreys family: genealogical notes; coat of arms, [Temp, 19th cent.] (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - [B., E.]
      - "David Humphreys." [From Herring, James, and James B. Longacre, The National Portrait Gallery of Distinguished Americans… New York, c. 1835, pt. xxii, pp. 1-10,], [ca. 1835] (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - 5 engravings re: David Humphreys; Grave Monument of Humphreys at New Haven, Connecticut; Humphreysville [Derby], Connecticut, undated (Box 4, Folder 163)
- GEORGE WILLIAM ERVING PAPERS, 1803-1808; Series II; 1" (1/5 box)
  This small series contains diplomatic papers of George William Erving (1769-1850), dating for the most part from his service as chargé d'affaires for the United States in Madrid from 1804 to 1809. No correspondence of Erving is preserved here. A memoranda book in the form of a diary records his activities in Madrid between October 1805 and February 1806, with scattered entries through July 1808. Erving describes political and diplomatic developments in Spain and gives in some detail several conversations with Spanish government officials. There are also occasional notes about social and economic conditions and about Erving's finances. Accompanying this volume is a miscellany of newspapers and other printed matter and copies of letters and documents in English, Spanish, and French, all pertaining to Spain and her American colonies, and to the progress of the Napoleonic Wars.
  - Diplomatic Journals
    - "Memoranda Book", 1805-1808 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Diplomatic Miscellany
    - L[ivingston], Robert] R., 1746-1813, and James M[onroe], 1758-1831
      - Copy of letter to [Francois, Marquis de Barbe-]Marbois, 1745-1837, with an undated memorandum on verso [by George W. Erving?] concerning the purchase of Florida by the United States, [pre-1803 May 3] (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - [Barbe-]Marbois, [Francis, Marquis de], 1745-1837
      - Copy of letter to R[obert] R. Livingston and J[ames] M[onroe], dated "14 Floreal An, 11", [1803 May 3] (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - [Erving, George W., 1769-1850]
      - "Summary of Impress[ments?] sent to the Secy of State with my letter Sep.l. 1804 No. 43", [1804 September 1] (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Gazeta Extraordinaria de Madrid del Sabado 25 de Enero de 1806 [25 Jan 1806], Num. 9., endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "Peace, between France and Austria 27 Decr. 1805, Vienna", [1806 January 25] (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Printed broadside, in Spanish, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "Spanish decree of Blockade 21 Novr. 1806", [1806 November 21] (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Erving, George W., 1769-1850
      - Memorandum endorsed: "Hasty Observations upon Napoleon's Proclamation of Blockade Madrid Decr. 16, 1806", [1806 December 16] (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Decres, [Dennis de Cres, Duc], 1761-1820
      - 2 letters to John Armstrong (copies?), 1806 December 24, 1807 March 20 (Box 5, Folder 169)
      - English translations of same endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "Decisions of the Council of Prizes in ye Case of the Hibirnia and the Minister of Marine his letters to Genl Armstrong", 1806 December 24, 1807 March 20 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Memorandum in French, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "Spanish Loans Made in Holland May 1807", 1807 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Memorandum in Spanish, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "A Decree of Acquittal given at Bilboa - 20th July 1807 in the Case of the Shepherdess", 1807 July 20 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Gazette Nationale ou le Moniteur Universel, 25 Juillet 1807, No. 206, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "Mr. Erving at Madrid. Peace between Russia and France", 1807 July 25 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Gazeta Extraordinaria de Madrid del Domingo 2 de Agosto de 1807 [2 Aug 1807], Num. 69, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "Treaty between France and Russia", 1807 August 2 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Another copy, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "Peace between France and Russia 9 July 1807", 1807 August 2 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Gazeta de Madrid del Viernes 21 de Agosto de 1807 [21 Aug 1807], Num. 75, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "President's Proclamation July 2 1807", 1807 August 21 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - [Erving, George W., 1769-1850?]
      - Memorandum endorsed "French Decree Sep. 17. 1807", [1807 September 17] (Box 5, Folder 173)
      - Memorandum endorsed "British Decree, 1807 Novr 1807" (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Copy of British order-in-council re French naval blockade [issued 16 Nov 1807], 1807 November 11 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Newspaper clipping re American shipping embargo issued 22 Dec 1807, [1807 December ?] (Box 5, Folder 174)